This origin of this asymmetry occurs when you have the movement of the notochordal
这种不对称的起源发生在你拥有原索过程的运动时
process.
脊索。
It will create a node here called Hensen's node.
它会在这里形成一个我们称之为N-Sense结的结。
We find another image of this node, it's here, now that it's down here.
我们找到了这个结的另一张图片，它在这里，现在它在下面。
We'll find another image, it's here now, you see, there.
我们会找到另一张图片，它现在在这里，你看，在那里。
This is the movement, what we call the rise of the formation of this
这就是我们所说的这个运动，即这个脊索轴形成的高潮。
notochordal axis.
脊索轴。
Do you remember?
你们还记得吗？
If I go inside now...
如果我现在进入内部...
What do I see? I see that on this structure, inside,
我看到了什么？我看到在这个结构上，内部有微小的迹象。
there are micro-signs.
有微小的迹象。
It was thanks to Kartagener's syndrome that Japanese researchers discovered the system.
正是由于卡塔格纳综合征，日本人发现了这个系统。
They realized that there was always a laterality disorder
他们发现，每次那些心脏长在右边而不是左边的人，都会出现侧向性问题。
in people who developed their heart on the right instead of the left.
那些心脏长在右边而不是左边的人。
They started searching and found these small signs for the first time.
他们开始研究，在哪里第一次发现了这些小迹象。
In life, in the body, there are many of these small signs.
在生命中，在身体里，有很多这样的小迹象。
Spermatozoa.
精子。
these small cilia, in the uterus and in the fallopian tubes there are these small cilia, in the
这些小纤毛，在子宫和输卵管里有这些小纤毛，在支气管里有这些小纤毛，等等。他们第一次发现，在亨森结的内部，他们观察到也有小纤毛，但它们不是来回摆动，而是旋转运动。
bronchi you have these small cilia, etc. And for the first time, they discovered, in
支气管里有这些小纤毛，等等。他们第一次发现，在
the part of Hensen's node, inside, they observed that there were small
亨森结的内部，他们观察到也有小纤毛，但它们不是来回摆动，而是旋转运动。
cilia too, but they weren't moving back and forth, but in a rotary
纤毛，但它们不是来回摆动，而是旋转运动。
motion. You see, there are small cilia here. Imagine here that this is
旋转的。你看，这里有小纤毛。你想象一下这里是亨森结，它在移动，它在这里，旁边就是这些小纤毛。
Hensen's node
是亨森结
moving, which is here, and right next to it are these small cilia.
的亨森结在移动，它在这里，旁边就是这些小纤毛。
and each time it's cells and then there's like a small snow of tissue that we call small
每次都是细胞，然后就像有一层小小的组织雪花，我们称之为小囊泡，你看，我们称之为囊泡，它们在这里聚集，然后这些小纤毛旋转，实际上它们倾斜了60度，当它们旋转时，当它们远离底部光线时，它们会加速，形成这样的运动，所以它将这些小分子集中到一边，被推到胚胎的左侧。
vesicles, you see, that we call vesicles here that
小囊泡，你看，我们称之为囊泡，它们在这里聚集，然后这些小纤毛旋转，实际上它们倾斜了60度，当它们旋转时，当它们远离底部光线时，它们会加速，形成这样的运动，所以它将这些小分子集中到一边，被推到胚胎的左侧。
concentrate here and then
聚集在这里，然后
there are these small cilia that rotate and in fact they are tilted at 60 degrees
这些小纤毛旋转，实际上它们倾斜了60度
and when they
当它们
rotate they have an acceleration when they are far from the light of the lower part
旋转时，当它们远离底部光线时，它们会加速
it makes
它会形成
a movement like this, okay, so it
这样的运动，好的，所以它会
concentrates these small molecules
将这些小分子集中
on one side, which are pushed
到一边，被推到
to the left side
胚胎的左侧。
of the embryo. These small
这些小
vesicles burst
囊泡破裂
and release a new small, subtle
并释放出新的微小雪花
snow of pre-morphogenetic
的分子
molecules, which means you'll have
前形态发生，这使得你拥有
an internal asymmetry that will develop.
一个将要发展的内在不对称。
The heart will develop
心脏将要发展
more on the left, the liver, etc.
更多地偏向左侧，肝脏等。
And that will develop all this asymmetry.
这将发展出所有这些不对称。
In your body,
在你的身体里，
on the outside, you appear
从外部看，你似乎
rather symmetrical, but inside, you have a great asymmetry.
相当对称，但内部却有很大的不对称。
Whether it's on the cerebral, ocular level, etc., etc.,
无论是大脑、眼睛等等，
all the way through your body.
直到你的全身。
It's an axis that runs between your sacrum and the base of your skull.
这是一条介于你的骶骨和颅底之间的轴线。
It's the flow of your embryo's asymmetry.
这是你胚胎不对称的流动。
So its laterality organization.
因此，它的侧向组织。
You have a cascade of these small molecules
你有一连串的这些小分子
that will release proteins.
它们将释放蛋白质。
specific ones called sonic hedgehog, specific genes with zinc,
我们称之为声波刺猬（sonotique headhutch）的特定基因，含有锌等，
etc.,
等等，
which will actually activate on one side what we call the
它们实际上会激活一侧我们称之为
caronte system and hypercalcium.
钙调蛋白（caronté）和高钙（hypercalcium）系统。
And this calcium activity is what intervenes in the development of
而这种钙活性，正是它参与了细胞的
cells
细胞
for faster development on one side than on the other.
为了使一侧比另一侧发展得更快。